u =[
    {
      "Front": "апельсин",
      "Back": "orange"
    },
    {
      "Front": "банан",
      "Back": "banana"
    },
    {
      "Front": "бифштекс",
      "Back": "steak"
    },
    {
      "Front": "борщ",
      "Back": "borsch"
    },
    {
      "Front": "бублик",
      "Back": "bagel"
    },
    {
      "Front": "булка",
      "Back": "white bread"
    },
    {
      "Front": "булочка",
      "Back": "small roll"
    },
    {
      "Front": "бульон",
      "Back": "buillon"
    },
    {
      "Front": "бутерброд",
      "Back": "open-faced sandwich"
    },
    {
      "Front": "вино",
      "Back": "wine"
    },
    {
      "Front": "виноград",
      "Back": "grapes"
    },
    {
      "Front": "вода",
      "Back": "water"
    },
    {
      "Front": "гамбургер",
      "Back": "hamburger"
    },
    {
      "Front": "горчица	",
      "Back": "mustard"
    },
    {
      "Front": "гриб",
      "Back": "mushroom"
    },
    {
      "Front": "закуски",
      "Back": "appetizers"
    },
    {
      "Front": "икра",
      "Back": "caviar"
    },
    {
      "Front": "капуста",
      "Back": "cabbage"
    },
    {
      "Front": "картофель",
      "Back": "potato/potatoes"
    },
    {
      "Front": "каша",
      "Back": "hot cereal"
    },
    {
      "Front": "кефир",
      "Back": "kefir"
    },
    {
      "Front": "колбаса",
      "Back": "sausage"
    },
    {
      "Front": "конфеты",
      "Back": "candy"
    },
    {
      "Front": "котлета",
      "Back": "cutlet"
    },
    {
      "Front": "котлеты по-киевски",
      "Back": "chicken Kiev"
    },
    {
      "Front": "кофе",
      "Back": "coffee"
    },
    {
      "Front": "курица",
      "Back": "chicken"
    },
    {
      "Front": "лимон",
      "Back": "lemon"
    },
    {
      "Front": "лук",
      "Back": "onion(s)"
    },
    {
      "Front": "макароны",
      "Back": "macaroni"
    },
    {
      "Front": "масло",
      "Back": "butter"
    },
    {
      "Front": "минеральная вода",
      "Back": "mineral water"
    },
    {
      "Front": "молоко",
      "Back": "milk"
    },
    {
      "Front": "морковь",
      "Back": "carrot(s)"
    },
    {
      "Front": "мороженое",
      "Back": "ice cream"
    },
    {
      "Front": "мясо",
      "Back": "meat"
    },
    {
      "Front": "мясное ассорти",
      "Back": "cold cuts assortment"
    },
    {
      "Front": "напиток",
      "Back": "drink"
    },
    {
      "Front": "овощи",
      "Back": "vegetables"
    },
    {
      "Front": "огурец",
      "Back": "cucumber"
    },
    {
      "Front": "оливье",
      "Back": "potato salad with chicken"
    },
    {
      "Front": "пельмени",
      "Back": "pelmeni"
    },
    {
      "Front": "перец",
      "Back": "pepper"
    },
    {
      "Front": "печенье",
      "Back": "cookie"
    },
    {
      "Front": "пиво",
      "Back": "beer"
    },
    {
      "Front": "пирожки",
      "Back": "baked or fried dumplings"
    },
    {
      "Front": "пицца",
      "Back": "pizza"
    },
    {
      "Front": "помидор",
      "Back": "tomato"
    },
    {
      "Front": "пюре",
      "Back": "creamy mashed potatoes"
    },
    {
      "Front": "рис",
      "Back": "rice"
    },
    {
      "Front": "рыба",
      "Back": "fish"
    },
    {
      "Front": "салат",
      "Back": "salad"
    },
    {
      "Front": "сахар",
      "Back": "sugar"
    },
    {
      "Front": "сладкое",
      "Back": "dessert"
    },
    {
      "Front": "сметана",
      "Back": "sour cream"
    },
    {
      "Front": "сок",
      "Back": "juice"
    },
    {
      "Front": "соль",
      "Back": "salt"
    },
    {
      "Front": "соус",
      "Back": "sauce"
    },
    {
      "Front": "суп",
      "Back": "soup"
    },
    {
      "Front": "сыр",
      "Back": "cheese"
    },
    {
      "Front": "тесто",
      "Back": "dough"
    },
    {
      "Front": "торт",
      "Back": "cake"
    },
    {
      "Front": "фарш",
      "Back": "ground meat"
    },
    {
      "Front": "фрукты",
      "Back": "fruit"
    },
    {
      "Front": "хлеб",
      "Back": "bread"
    },
    {
      "Front": "чай",
      "Back": "tea"
    },
    {
      "Front": "чеснок",
      "Back": "garlic"
    },
    {
      "Front": "шашлык",
      "Back": "shish kabob"
    },
    {
      "Front": "щи",
      "Back": "cabbage soup"
    },
    {
      "Front": "яблоко",
      "Back": "apple"
    },
    {
      "Front": "яичница",
      "Back": "cooked (not boiled) eggs"
    },
    {
      "Front": "яйцо",
      "Back": "egg"
    },
    {
      "Front": "буфет",
      "Back": "snack bar"
    },
    {
      "Front": "булочная",
      "Back": "bakery"
    },
    {
      "Front": "гастроном",
      "Back": "grocery store"
    },
    {
      "Front": "кафе",
      "Back": "cafe"
    },
    {
      "Front": "кафетерий",
      "Back": "snack bar"
    },
    {
      "Front": "продовольственный магазин",
      "Back": "grocery store"
    },
    {
      "Front": "универсам",
      "Back": "self-service grocery store"
    },
    {
      "Front": "аллергия",
      "Back": "allergy"
    },
    {
      "Front": "вегетарианец/вегетерианка",
      "Back": "vegetarian"
    },
    {
      "Front": "блюдо",
      "Back": "dish"
    },
    {
      "Front": "бутылка",
      "Back": "bottle"
    },
    {
      "Front": "второе",
      "Back": "main course"
    },
    {
      "Front": "копейка",
      "Back": "kopeck"
    },
    {
      "Front": "кухня",
      "Back": "cuisine, style of cooking"
    },
    {
      "Front": "меню",
      "Back": "menu"
    },
    {
      "Front": "официант/официанка",
      "Back": "waiter/waitress"
    },
    {
      "Front": "первое",
      "Back": "first course (always soup)"
    },
    {
      "Front": "порция",
      "Back": "portion"
    },
    {
      "Front": "продукты",
      "Back": "groceries"
    },
    {
      "Front": "счёт",
      "Back": "bill, check"
    },
    {
      "Front": "чаевые",
      "Back": "tip"
    },
    {
      "Front": "вкусный",
      "Back": "tasty, good"
    },
    {
      "Front": "минеральный",
      "Back": "mineral"
    },
    {
      "Front": "молочный",
      "Back": "milk, dairy"
    },
    {
      "Front": "мясной",
      "Back": "meat"
    },
    {
      "Front": "никакой",
      "Back": "none"
    },
    {
      "Front": "свежий",
      "Back": "fresh"
    },
    {
      "Front": "томатный",
      "Back": "tomato"
    },
    {
      "Front": "быть",
      "Back": "to be"
    },
    {
      "Front": "брать/взять",
      "Back": "to take"
    },
    {
      "Front": "готовить/приготовить",
      "Back": "to cook, prepare"
    },
    {
      "Front": "делать/сделать",
      "Back": "to do, make"
    },
    {
      "Front": "думать/подумать",
      "Back": "to think"
    },
    {
      "Front": "есть/съесть",
      "Back": "to eat"
    },
    {
      "Front": "заказывать",
      "Back": "to order"
    },
    {
      "Front": "идти/пойти",
      "Back": "to go (on foot or within a city)"
    },
    {
      "Front": "найти",
      "Back": "to find"
    },
    {
      "Front": "обедать/пообедать",
      "Back": "to have lunch"
    },
    {
      "Front": "писать/написать",
      "Back": "to write"
    },
    {
      "Front": "пить/выпить",
      "Back": "to drink"
    },
    {
      "Front": "показывать/показать",
      "Back": "to show"
    },
    {
      "Front": "покупать/купить",
      "Back": "to buy"
    },
    {
      "Front": "попасть",
      "Back": "to manage to get in"
    },
    {
      "Front": "рассказывать/рассказать",
      "Back": "to narrate, tell (a story)"
    },
    {
      "Front": "решать/решить",
      "Back": "to decide"
    },
    {
      "Front": "слышать/слушать",
      "Back": "to hear"
    },
    {
      "Front": "смотреть/посмотреть",
      "Back": "to watch"
    },
    {
      "Front": "советовать/посоветовать",
      "Back": "to advise"
    },
    {
      "Front": "ужинать/поунжинать",
      "Back": "to have supper"
    },
    {
      "Front": "пока",
      "Back": "meanwhile"
    },
    {
      "Front": "просто",
      "Back": "simply, just"
    },
    {
      "Front": "страшно",
      "Back": "terribly"
    },
    {
      "Front": "без",
      "Back": "without"
    },
    {
      "Front": "с",
      "Back": "with"
    },
    {
      "Front": "нельзя",
      "Back": "it is not permitted"
    }
    {
      "Front": "Во-первых..., Во-вторых...",
      "Back": "In the first place..., in the second place..."
    },
    {
      "Front": "Дайте, пожалуйста, счёт!",
      "Back": "Check, please!"
    },
    {
      "Front": "Если говорить о себе, то...",
      "Back": "If I use myself as an example, then..."
    },
    {
      "Front": "Минуточку!",
      "Back": "Just a minute!"
    },
    {
      "Front": "Мы точно попадём.",
      "Back": "We'll get in for sure."
    },
    {
      "Front": "Получите!",
      "Back": "Take it! (said when paying)"
    },
    {
      "Front": "Пошли!",
      "Back": "Let's go!"
    },
    {
      "Front": "Принесите, пожалуйста, меню!.",
      "Back": "Please bring a menu."
    },
    {
      "Front": "Смотря...",
      "Back": "It depends..."
    },
    {
      "Front": "С одной стороны..., с другой стороны...",
      "Back": "On the one hand..., on the other hand..."
    },
    {
      "Front": "Что вы (нам, мне) посоветуете взять?",
      "Back": "What do you advise (us, me) to order?"
    },
    {
      "Front": "Что ещё нужно?",
      "Back": "What else is needed?"
    }
  ]